<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Project Portfolio on Danny Garcia</title>
    <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Project Portfolio on Danny Garcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 11:13:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Car Prices Prediction Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/3_car-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/3_car-prices/</guid>
      <description>For this project, I created a K-Nearest-Neighbors model to help predict car prices based upon the best features of automobiles in the corresponding dataset. Some questions that I attempted to answer were: -Which features give us the lowest RMSE score? -For which value of the hyperparameter K gives us the best performance? -Is a Univariate or Multivariate model better for predicting the price?
While not necessarily the most robust algorithm, the K-Nearest-Neighbors model is a fundamental Machine Learning algorithm to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMS Spam Messages Classification Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/4_sms-classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/4_sms-classifier/</guid>
      <description>One of the major problems plaguing technologically advanced society is the never ending amount of robocalls and spam text messages. For this project, I created a Classification model that helps predict if a given message is spam or not. The following techniques were used in this project:
Multinomial Naive Bayes was used to calculate the probability of a message being spam given the words in the messge. Conditional probability fundamentals were useed in order to calculate all of the necessary elements of the Naive Bayes algorithm formula.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Prices Regression Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/1_house_prices_iowa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/1_house_prices_iowa/</guid>
      <description>Attempting to find a “deal” on a piece of real estate is a problem that has plagued investors for years. Luckily, thanks to a data set provided by the Housing Prices Kaggle competition, I was able to create a Regression model that is able to accurately depict the prices of homes in a small town in Iowa. There were many technical skills involved in this project, but some of the problems that I had to overcome were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lottery Addiction Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/10_lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/10_lottery/</guid>
      <description>With the continuation of the complete legalization of Sports betting across the US, one could expect that the number of gambling addicts across the country will continue to increase. This project is meant to help individuals addicted to playing the lottery visualize how slim their chances are of winning by answering the following questions:
What is the probability of winning the big prize in a single ticket? What is the probability of winning a prize if we play 40 tickets?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fandango Movie Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/5_fandango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/5_fandango/</guid>
      <description>In 2015, there was a scandle involving the movie rating site Fandango in which they were accused of rating movies too high by rounding up ratings to the nearest star. Admitting that there was a bug, Fandango released a statement saying the issue had been resolved beginning in 2016. However, they provided no proof of fixes. The goal of this project is to answer the following questions:
Did Fandango keep their word when they announced they had fixed the rating issue?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titanic Classification Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/2_titanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/2_titanic/</guid>
      <description>As part of a competition on Kaggle, I created this Machine Learning project to try and predict which passengers survived the tragic sinking of the Titanic. It follows a standard ML workflow, whereby we create our data matrix, define our feature and target vectors, and fit our classification model (Logistic Regression is the model I chose). However, in order to do so, we had to answer the following questions:
Which features are the best choices to use for our model?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars Survey Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/13_starwars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/13_starwars/</guid>
      <description>Since the release of the recent “Obi-Wan” spinoff show on Disney+, what better way to celebrate than to perform data analysis on a Star Wars survey for a project? The data set was assembled by the company FiveThirtyEight, and throughout this project we look to answer the following questions:
Which Episode to people enjoy the most? How many people have seen each episode? Is there a split in results between males and females?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIA Factbook SQL Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/14_cia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/14_cia/</guid>
      <description>Standard Query Language (SQL) is one of the most quintessential tools to possess in order to begin to interact with RDBMSs. In this project, we use a data set published by the CIA that contains data on many of the worlds countries. We leverage this data set in order to anser the following questions:
What is the average population for each country on earth? What is the average size of each country on the planet?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Learning Advertisement Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/6_advertisement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/6_advertisement/</guid>
      <description>For this project, we imagine that we work for a popular e-learning platform that teaches coding (eg Coursera, Udemy, etc.). Management has expressed interest in increasing the advertising budget and wishes to begin a new marketing campaign in two markets. The goal of this project is to answer the following questions:
Which kinds of topics are potential learners interested in? Which two markets are the best for advertisement? How much would potential learners in those markets be willing to pay for our product?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Analysis for I-94</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/11-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/11-traffic/</guid>
      <description>For this project, we wish to analyze traffic volume for a section of the I-94 expressway in Minnesota between Minneapolis and Saint Paul. Some of the questions that we wish to answer are:
Is there a time of day where traffic volume is the most heavy? Is there a difference in travel patterns on weekends as opposed to weekdays? Do certain types of weather have an impact on traffic volume? With the amount of travel only increasing after the pandemic, perhaps a company like Uber or Door Dash would like to know precisely when traffic will be bad so they can prepare or avoid these above average travel times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employee Exit Surveys Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/12_employees/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/12_employees/</guid>
      <description>In an era where it appears that the average tenure for an employee continues to decline, it is relevant for any organization to gain insight into just exactly why employees are leaving their jobs so soon. For this project, we take a closer look at this issue to determine the following:
Are employees with short tenures leaving their jobs due to some kind of dissatisfaction? Does this trend translate to employees with longer tenures as well?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euro vs. USD Analysis</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/7_eur_usd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/7_eur_usd/</guid>
      <description>No project on my portfolio is probably more relevant than this one. For all of 2022, the Federal Reserve’s FOMC has been hiking interest rates in an attempt to curb inflation that is boarderline run-away. This project takes a look at the value of the Euro compared to the USD to examine the following:
Did the slashing of interest rates during the 2008 Recession strengthen or weaken the Euro compared to the USD?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App Store Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/15_app_store/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/15_app_store/</guid>
      <description>This project analyzes apps on both the Google Playstore and the App Store. The analysis looks at the following features of apps on each respective appstore:
The number of free apps on either store The most popular genres of apps The most popular apps based on installations or downloads The idea behind this project is, if I were approached by employers who were considering launching an app, what insights could I provide?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker News Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/9_hacker_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/9_hacker_news/</guid>
      <description>For this project, we examine the posts from a popular technology news website called Hacker News. There are two different types of posts that users can submit to the Hacker News website, “Ask HN” and “Show HN”. The former posts are used to ask a question, whereas the latter are used to impart content that users find interesting or insightful. We seek to answer two questions in this analysis:
Which type of posts, on average, receive more comments?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legacy Automation Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/8_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/8_automation/</guid>
      <description>This project is one that I created to assist me with a daily report that I run each day for work. I was able to automate a 40 minute process and condense it down to 2 minutes. Please note that the workflow will appear somewhat vague as I would rather not disclose any remotely sensitive information about our processes. While I try to describe the flow via comments as best I can in the source code, here is a brief summary of what is required by this process each day:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>As a Summa Cum Laude graduate from the University of Illinois at Chicago, I&amp;rsquo;m proud of the problem solving skillset that I have been able to develop, not just in university, but also in the field. As a Liquidity Data Analyst in the Treasury Department of Northern Trust, our team is routinely expected to pull together information from a variety of sources to help provide meaningul insight and guidance for senior management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Check out my other websites as well.
Website URL LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielj-garcia/ GitHub: https://github.com/musicmaster81 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
