<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Danny Garcia</title>
    <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Danny Garcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco Crime Multiclass Classification Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/25_san_fran_crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/25_san_fran_crime/</guid>
      <description>This project is a terminated Kaggle competition that attempts to predict the type of crime a San Francisco criminal may commit depending on the features of the dataset. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it to Kaggle to come up with a more comprehensive introduction.
&amp;ldquo;From 1934 to 1963, San Francisco was infamous for housing some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most notorious criminals on the inescapable island of Alcatraz.
Today, the city is known more for its tech scene than its criminal past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TensorFlow Image Classification Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/24_fashion_cnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/24_fashion_cnn/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks are a quintessential model in the Machine Learning realm due to their potency and relative simplicity. This is definitely an area that I am trying to grow in. While their implementation is rather simple, the knowledge of how they work is not intuitive. For this project in particular, we harness the power of TensorFlow and Keras to create a Convoluted Neural Network to perform multiclass classification on pieces of clothing from the MINST Fashion data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin Price Prediction Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/23_bitcoin-prediction-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/23_bitcoin-prediction-project/</guid>
      <description>Love it or hate it, Bitcoin has changed the investment landscape forever. On one hand, you have bulls like Kevin O&amp;rsquo;Leary proclaiming it will be the next sector of the stock market, while on the other hand the number of bears to count are just too many. Regardless of your opinion of it, it is a viable investment alternative, and as such, we can utilize Machine Learning techniques to help determine whether the price of Bitcoin will go up or down tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FIFA Player Clustering Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/22_soccer_player_clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/22_soccer_player_clustering/</guid>
      <description>While Supervised Machine Learning Algorithms are great, unlabeled data tends to hold the potential for generating truly innovative new insights. K-Means Clustering is one of the most powerful unsupervised Machine Learning algorithms used for finding patterns in unlabeled data. For this project, we built a K-Means clustering algorithm to detect patterns amongst soccer players using a dataset from the EA Sports FIFA 22 videogame. Some questions that we had to answer during this project were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baseball WAR Statistic Prediction Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/21_baseball_war_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/21_baseball_war_prediction/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps the most quintessential of the major four American sports, baseball appears to be growing in popularity at a rapid pace. I can say this because, as a former baseball player myself, the amount of media coverage being given to the sport has increased substantially since I played about a decade ago. With the rise of advanced analytics and the ascension of sports betting to the mainstream, now more than ever, coaches and fans alike are reliant upon statistics to make or break their real (or fantasy) teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New and Improved Titanic Classification Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/20_new-and-improved-titanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/20_new-and-improved-titanic/</guid>
      <description>Earlier in my Project Portfolio&amp;rsquo;s history, I created a Machine Learning algorithm to predict the survivors of the Titanic using datasets from the Kaggle competition by the same name. However, this project was created in the early stages of my Machine Learning &amp;ldquo;learning&amp;rdquo; curve (pun intended).
This time, I&amp;rsquo;m back for a second try with all of the additional knowledge of an employment ready ML Engineer (i.e, feature engineering, cross validation, hyperparameter optimization, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Risk Prediction Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/19_credit_model_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/19_credit_model_project/</guid>
      <description>One of the most fundamental tenets of society here in America is the concept of loans and debt. From the national down to the individual level, debt is used liberally and often without restraint. Corporations like banks and credit unions realize this fact, and as a result, are able to make money off of this system by loaning money to needy individuals at an interest rate that generates some kind of ROI for these companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Rentals Prediction Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/17_bike-rentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/17_bike-rentals/</guid>
      <description>Having attended University in downtown Chicago, one of the best ways to travel in a heavily condensed urban area is via bicycle. Never to waste a chance to make a quick profit, the City of Chicago launched a bike rental program called Divvy in which riders can rent a bike to travel from point A to point B. For this project, we imagine we are employed by a company like Divvy and recently received a request to predict how many bike rentals will occurr on a given day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handwritten Digits Classifier</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/18_digits_classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/18_digits_classifier/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks are some of the most powerful models any Machine Learning Engineer can construct. This project is designed to classify images of handwritten numbers based upon the composition of the image. In order to construct a viable model, I had to answer the following questions:
How can we ensure that our Neural Network does not overfit the training data? How many hidden layers are needed to increase our accuracy as much as possible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Market Prediction Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/16_stockmarket/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/16_stockmarket/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of the past year, the stock market has experienced an substantial amount of volatility thanks to the Federal Reserve raising interest rates in an attempt to curb inflation. Needles to say, retail investor&amp;rsquo;s portfolios are down, on average, about 33% this year. As an individual who is also invested in this bear market, I would love if there was a way to predict the market to help prevent losses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Prices Prediction Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/3_car-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/3_car-prices/</guid>
      <description>For this project, I created a K-Nearest-Neighbors model to help predict car prices based upon the best features of automobiles in the corresponding dataset. Some questions that I attempted to answer were: -Which features give us the lowest RMSE score? -For which value of the hyperparameter K gives us the best performance? -Is a Univariate or Multivariate model better for predicting the price?
While not necessarily the most robust algorithm, the K-Nearest-Neighbors model is a fundamental Machine Learning algorithm to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMS Spam Messages Classification Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/4_sms-classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/4_sms-classifier/</guid>
      <description>One of the major problems plaguing technologically advanced society is the never ending amount of robocalls and spam text messages. For this project, I created a Classification model that helps predict if a given message is spam or not. The following techniques were used in this project:
Multinomial Naive Bayes was used to calculate the probability of a message being spam given the words in the messge. Conditional probability fundamentals were useed in order to calculate all of the necessary elements of the Naive Bayes algorithm formula.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Prices Regression Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/1_house_prices_iowa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/1_house_prices_iowa/</guid>
      <description>Attempting to find a “deal” on a piece of real estate is a problem that has plagued investors for years. Luckily, thanks to a data set provided by the Housing Prices Kaggle competition, I was able to create a Regression model that is able to accurately depict the prices of homes in a small town in Iowa. There were many technical skills involved in this project, but some of the problems that I had to overcome were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lottery Addiction Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/10_lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/10_lottery/</guid>
      <description>With the continuation of the complete legalization of Sports betting across the US, one could expect that the number of gambling addicts across the country will continue to increase. This project is meant to help individuals addicted to playing the lottery visualize how slim their chances are of winning by answering the following questions:
What is the probability of winning the big prize in a single ticket? What is the probability of winning a prize if we play 40 tickets?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fandango Movie Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/5_fandango/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/5_fandango/</guid>
      <description>In 2015, there was a scandle involving the movie rating site Fandango in which they were accused of rating movies too high by rounding up ratings to the nearest star. Admitting that there was a bug, Fandango released a statement saying the issue had been resolved beginning in 2016. However, they provided no proof of fixes. The goal of this project is to answer the following questions:
Did Fandango keep their word when they announced they had fixed the rating issue?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titanic Classification Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/2_titanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/2_titanic/</guid>
      <description>As part of a competition on Kaggle, I created this Machine Learning project to try and predict which passengers survived the tragic sinking of the Titanic. It follows a standard ML workflow, whereby we create our data matrix, define our feature and target vectors, and fit our classification model (Logistic Regression is the model I chose). However, in order to do so, we had to answer the following questions:
Which features are the best choices to use for our model?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars Survey Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/13_starwars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/13_starwars/</guid>
      <description>Since the release of the recent “Obi-Wan” spinoff show on Disney+, what better way to celebrate than to perform data analysis on a Star Wars survey for a project? The data set was assembled by the company FiveThirtyEight, and throughout this project we look to answer the following questions:
Which Episode to people enjoy the most? How many people have seen each episode? Is there a split in results between males and females?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIA Factbook SQL Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/14_cia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/14_cia/</guid>
      <description>Standard Query Language (SQL) is one of the most quintessential tools to possess in order to begin to interact with RDBMSs. In this project, we use a data set published by the CIA that contains data on many of the worlds countries. We leverage this data set in order to anser the following questions:
What is the average population for each country on earth? What is the average size of each country on the planet?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Learning Advertisement Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/6_advertisement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/6_advertisement/</guid>
      <description>For this project, we imagine that we work for a popular e-learning platform that teaches coding (eg Coursera, Udemy, etc.). Management has expressed interest in increasing the advertising budget and wishes to begin a new marketing campaign in two markets. The goal of this project is to answer the following questions:
Which kinds of topics are potential learners interested in? Which two markets are the best for advertisement? How much would potential learners in those markets be willing to pay for our product?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Analysis for I-94</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/11-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/11-traffic/</guid>
      <description>For this project, we wish to analyze traffic volume for a section of the I-94 expressway in Minnesota between Minneapolis and Saint Paul. Some of the questions that we wish to answer are:
Is there a time of day where traffic volume is the most heavy? Is there a difference in travel patterns on weekends as opposed to weekdays? Do certain types of weather have an impact on traffic volume? With the amount of travel only increasing after the pandemic, perhaps a company like Uber or Door Dash would like to know precisely when traffic will be bad so they can prepare or avoid these above average travel times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employee Exit Surveys Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/12_employees/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/12_employees/</guid>
      <description>In an era where it appears that the average tenure for an employee continues to decline, it is relevant for any organization to gain insight into just exactly why employees are leaving their jobs so soon. For this project, we take a closer look at this issue to determine the following:
Are employees with short tenures leaving their jobs due to some kind of dissatisfaction? Does this trend translate to employees with longer tenures as well?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euro vs. USD Analysis</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/7_eur_usd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/7_eur_usd/</guid>
      <description>No project on my portfolio is probably more relevant than this one. For all of 2022, the Federal Reserve’s FOMC has been hiking interest rates in an attempt to curb inflation that is boarderline run-away. This project takes a look at the value of the Euro compared to the USD to examine the following:
Did the slashing of interest rates during the 2008 Recession strengthen or weaken the Euro compared to the USD?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App Store Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/15_app_store/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/15_app_store/</guid>
      <description>This project analyzes apps on both the Google Playstore and the App Store. The analysis looks at the following features of apps on each respective appstore:
The number of free apps on either store The most popular genres of apps The most popular apps based on installations or downloads The idea behind this project is, if I were approached by employers who were considering launching an app, what insights could I provide?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker News Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/9_hacker_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/9_hacker_news/</guid>
      <description>For this project, we examine the posts from a popular technology news website called Hacker News. There are two different types of posts that users can submit to the Hacker News website, “Ask HN” and “Show HN”. The former posts are used to ask a question, whereas the latter are used to impart content that users find interesting or insightful. We seek to answer two questions in this analysis:
Which type of posts, on average, receive more comments?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legacy Automation Project</title>
      <link>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/8_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musicmaster81.github.io/Danny_Portfolio/post/8_automation/</guid>
      <description>This project is one that I created to assist me with a daily report that I run each day for work. I was able to automate a 40 minute process and condense it down to 2 minutes. Please note that the workflow will appear somewhat vague as I would rather not disclose any remotely sensitive information about our processes. While I try to describe the flow via comments as best I can in the source code, here is a brief summary of what is required by this process each day:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
